[{"id": "5e147a756ca6dac04a20ca4f", "question": "When did Thomas Jefferson purchase the territory of Louisiana?", "answer": "1803", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be5c", "question": "Oldest son Al was the first ringmaster of what famous circus?", "answer": "Ringling Brothers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f7122a9e54d890926f6db", "question": "Which country claims the island of Saipan as a commonwealth?", "answer": "USA -- Saipan is part of the Northern Mariana Islands, which is a commonwealth of the U.S.  Saipan is the seat of the government.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b052", "question": "Former Yugoslavian leader Josip Broz was also known by what other name?", "answer": "Tito", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921b", "question": "What instrument did Sting play with the band \"The Police\"?", "answer": "Bass guitar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5be580ca5415ba52ed6f0ab9", "question": "Doha is the capital of which West Asian country?", "answer": "Qatar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaa8", "question": "What is the largest Japanese island?", "answer": "Honshu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be86", "question": "What type of a tree killed Sonny Bono?", "answer": "Pine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398e2", "question": "Which sci-fi movie introduced HAL 9000?", "answer": "2001: A Space Odyssey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133930a", "question": "In the 1982 movie \"E.T. The Extra-Terrestrial\", who plays Elliot's younger sister?", "answer": "Drew Barrymore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c277", "question": "What is October's birthstone?", "answer": "Opal", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69dda20565ad31a57c77e", "question": "What is the largest surviving Roman triumphal arch in the world?", "answer": "Arch of Constantine", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8b6", "question": "In what city would you find Balboa Park?", "answer": "San Diego", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b965", "question": "How many sheets of paper are there in a ream?", "answer": "500", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59db77f10ab2c8f322317ff1", "question": "Which tennis star wore denim shorts during matches?", "answer": "Andre Agassi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cabd", "question": "What common affliction makes the lens of the eye go opaque?", "answer": "Cataracts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8a92c01dd7bf43be5e749", "question": "What animal is on Levi\u2019s logo?", "answer": "Horse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339059", "question": "Which author wrote \"The Duncton Chronicles\"?", "answer": "William Horwood", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395e5", "question": "Why did the Simpsons go to New York CIty?", "answer": "Retrieve a lost car", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a828", "question": "In which US city is the United States Naval Academy located?", "answer": "Annapolis, Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e91", "question": "What movie did the villain Norman Bates appear in?", "answer": "Psycho", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede6516ce05a3942286dfc", "question": "What Tim Burton movie follows a mischievous ghost famed for his striped suit?", "answer": "\"Beetlejuice\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b361", "question": "Which planet was discovered in 1846?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133affb", "question": "What war ended with the Treaty of Ghent?", "answer": "War of 1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa6c", "question": "In what country is the town of Liege?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015e1f1fe83fe1f2a824b9a", "question": "After changing sides during World War II, what was Italy's primary objective?", "answer": "It distracted Germany from accomplishing its main objectives", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b594", "question": "When was the game \"Scrabble\" first released?", "answer": "1948", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ecae4a7790ded87bb38fd8c", "question": "Who was the leading goalscorer for SKC in 2012?", "answer": "Kei Kamara", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe76af2eec85e375820b2ba", "question": "Which country has the most UNESCO World Heritage Sites?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca2b", "question": "What is James Dewar most famous for inventing?", "answer": "The vacuum flask", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6aa", "question": "Which side of a ship is \"starboard\"?", "answer": "Right", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a78f", "question": "Parma and Tuscany are regions of what country?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfaf", "question": "Taal is an alternative name for what language?", "answer": "Afrikaans", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ed", "question": "In popular literature, what is Princess Aurora's better-known name?", "answer": "Sleeping Beauty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5febd9de7e83c707845b217e", "question": "In the game of golf, the iconic \"Green Jacket\" is presented to the winner of which championship?", "answer": "Masters Tournament", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5cb70bb8f96e155acab35d26", "question": "What is the longest running Star Trek series of all time in terms of total episodes?", "answer": "Star Trek: The Next Generation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ad7e6c9b24f84e0b9f9ffb3", "question": "In computing, what does HTTP stand for?", "answer": "Hypertext Transfer Protocol", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b67d", "question": "For what game were two jokers originally included in a standard deck of playing cards?", "answer": "Euchre", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c22a", "question": "The fear of punishment is known as what?", "answer": "Poinephobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c32a", "question": "What part of the eye gives it color?", "answer": "The Iris", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5af25bccb63e5727cf5a485c", "question": "Who did Luther Vandross duet with in the 1992 single \"Best Things In Life Are Free\"?", "answer": "Janet Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4f5", "question": "On a map, what are the lines that run parallel to the equator called?", "answer": "Latitude", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a03d", "question": "Of what descent is Peter, on the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Irish", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a64", "question": "What were the first names of the two brothers who formed the band \"The Kinks\"?", "answer": "Ray & Dave", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338abc", "question": "Which Beatles song is partially in French?", "answer": "Michelle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4f0", "question": "What must a Las Vegas blackjack dealer do when they reaches 16?", "answer": "Take a card", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2d3", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"The G.I. General\"?", "answer": "Omar Bradley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58bb33a0e368446ca7bd6846", "question": "In \"The Wizard of Oz\", what was the lion in search of?", "answer": "Courage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b10f", "question": "At what Ohio university were four students shot to death during a 1970 anti-war demonstration?", "answer": "Kent State", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b810", "question": "What is traditionally hidden in a Mardi Gras king cake?", "answer": "A small plastic baby doll", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4afd49076251badbeabf", "question": "What was the first food to be intentionally microwaved?", "answer": "Popcorn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c005", "question": "What is the study of stamps called?", "answer": "Philately", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbb5", "question": "What was the first Pokemon to be trademarked?", "answer": "Mew", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b57186167df192a942e335e", "question": "Which continent would you find the \"Strait of Magellan\" in?", "answer": "South America", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f6fcda9e54d890926f6d3", "question": "The southernmost city in the world is located in which country?", "answer": "Chile -- Ushuaia, Argentina held the title until 2019, when Chilean authorities upgraded the town Puerto Williams to city status.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd81b95d0de9af39e9d467a", "question": "What's the longest running TV show of all time?", "answer": "Guiding Light", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ecae22b790ded87bb38fd87", "question": "Who directed the seminal 1972 science-fiction film Solaris?", "answer": "Andrei Tarkovsky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff3d0364f032c0db195b498", "question": "Who were the five claimants to the Emperor of Rome in \"The Year of the Five Emperors\"?", "answer": "Pertinax, Didius Julianus, Pescennius Niger, Clodius Albinus and Septimius Severus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ea6", "question": "In what comic strip would you find siblings Zoe, Hammy and Wren?", "answer": "Baby Blues", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133963b", "question": "Which Disney's cartoon character's love interest is named Faline?", "answer": "Bambi's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c15f", "question": "Fax is short for which word?", "answer": "Facsimile", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef93396ce05a3942286e8b", "question": "Frank Darabont seriously contemplated selling the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\" script to which person?", "answer": "Rob Reiner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc3106ce05a3942286f1d", "question": "Who played the role of Hannibal Lector in the film \"Manhunter\"?", "answer": "Brian Cox", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6000ed369a72b906b34e3cea", "question": "Which scientist formulated the law of universal gravitation?", "answer": "Sir Isaac Newton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0bc", "question": "What pseudonym was Norma McCorvey given in a historic 1973 Supreme Court ruling?", "answer": "Jane Roe", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c408877e98cb97778999", "question": "What is the highest waterfall in Africa?", "answer": "Tugela Falls", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8f3", "question": "What range contains the world's highest mountains not located in Asia?", "answer": "The Andes", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5909d246bb53d1af65886507", "question": "Which star is represented by placing a star on top of a Christmas tree?", "answer": "Star of Bethlehem", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a076", "question": "In which TV series does Fred Savage play Kevin Arnold?", "answer": "The Wonder Years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf29", "question": "What sporting event first took place in 1903?", "answer": "Tour de France", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393c2", "question": "How many US soldiers were killed in the movie \"Black Hawk Down\"?", "answer": "18", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a25f2f96682715b82711cef", "question": "What is Joseph Priestley credited with discovering?", "answer": "Oxygen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8e5", "question": "What color code represents a life-threatening emergency, in hospital lingo?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fedd8b06ce05a3942286d73", "question": "The Soup Nazi was an infamous character on which sitcom?", "answer": "\"Seinfeld\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6c7", "question": "Hurricane season in the North Atlantic officially begins on the first day of what month?", "answer": "June", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefbf206ce05a3942286efb", "question": "Who was the male lead in the film \"American Gigolo\"?", "answer": "Richard Gere", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a35e", "question": "Where is the International Court of Justice?", "answer": "The Hague", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdc0fed469bb8041d07a069", "question": "Which beer is from the \"land of sky blue waters\"?", "answer": "Hamm's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abad", "question": "Which US state is Baltimore located in?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133970d", "question": "Actor Jason Lee was a professional in which sport?", "answer": "Skateboarding", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ad", "question": "Who was the first host of \"The Tonight Show\"?", "answer": "Steve Allen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a89", "question": "According to legend, Robin Hood was born in what area of Nottinghamshire?", "answer": "Locksley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc2", "question": "Who is the Greek god of love?", "answer": "Eros", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b8", "question": "In the TV show \"Knight Rider\", what was the real last name of Michael Knight?", "answer": "Long", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c5e", "question": "What artist, who died in 1986, was famous for her Southwestern paintings?", "answer": "Georgia O\u2019Keefe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339395", "question": "Which actor from the cast of the movie \"Rain Man\" won an Oscar?", "answer": "Dustin Hoffmann", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ce", "question": "Where was Enrico Caruso born?", "answer": "Naples, Italy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010ca6f0775fa611bce67f8", "question": "The \"Malleus Maleficarum\" was a 15th-century guide to dealing with what?", "answer": "Witches -- Witch hunts spread across 15th century Europe, and hunters were guided by many books, including \"Malleus Maleficarum\".", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9cd", "question": "What is the more common term for sternum?", "answer": "Breastbone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339169", "question": "Who is The Friendly Ghost?", "answer": "Casper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4eed806d333868d34d776", "question": "Where did the croissant originate?", "answer": "Austria", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c339", "question": "What is the acronym for Thomas A. Swift's Electric Rifle?", "answer": "Taser", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6f2", "question": "What was New York's Bedloe's Island renamed in 1956?", "answer": "Liberty Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a34", "question": "What is the name of the chubby diva in the musical \"Fame\"?", "answer": "Mabel Washington", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4decd06d333868d34d71b", "question": "When did World War I officially end?", "answer": "November 11, 1918", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc3a", "question": "Prior to getting married, Kate Middleton worked as assistant accessory buyer at what clothing chain?", "answer": "Jigsaw", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dc9", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Archie Goodwin?", "answer": "Nero Wolfe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "590682eaff9c0647b50a80a2", "question": "What popular mobile game, that caused many players to get into accidents, was released in July of 2016?", "answer": "Pokemon Go", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133967d", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what color is the Simpson's refrigerator?", "answer": "Green", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133959b", "question": "What Oscar-winning movie features the quote \"What we do in life echoes in eternity\"?", "answer": "Gladiator", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6010c6a50775fa611bce67d2", "question": "Which 1990s computer program was launched without company approval?", "answer": "AOL Instant Messaging -- \u00a0In May 1997, a group of engineers quietly released Instant Messaging without permission -- for free!", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d27d2596a59cbdfbd38f", "question": "What is the most expensive spice by weight?", "answer": "Saffron", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ff", "question": "Who was Stan Laurel's partner?", "answer": "Oliver Hardy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339675", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what color is the tablecloth in the Simpsons' kitchen?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abd6", "question": "Nicosia is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Cyprus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fedda6a6ce05a3942286d85", "question": "What is Mr. Bean's actual first name?", "answer": "According to his television shows and movies, Mr. Bean's first name is actually \"Mr.\".", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f6", "question": "What Sponge cake is baked in the form of a female digit?", "answer": "Lady Fingers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b3704f1c3f17ccc40c8e12", "question": "Which English Member of Parliament referred to the pub as \"the heart of England\"?", "answer": "Samuel Pepys", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f9b7f6364247bf200fb879", "question": "Which Russian chemist created the modern periodic table?", "answer": "Dmitri Mendeleev", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0ed", "question": "What famous speech delivered on November 19, 1863, lasted only two minutes?", "answer": "Gettysburg Address", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389af", "question": "Whose wife was turned into a pillar of salt?", "answer": "Lot's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9e1", "question": "What birds were used by Japanese and Chinese fishermen to help catch fish?", "answer": "Cormorant", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6bb64fb6c85e9e634ff54", "question": "Whose fifth album was called \"Different Class\"?", "answer": "Pulp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8ab2b01dd7bf43be5e764", "question": "What does the term \"contrived patina\" mean?", "answer": "A weathered-looking surface", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c694", "question": "How many times did John Glenn circle the earth in 1962, when he became the first American in orbit?", "answer": "3", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9c5", "question": "What is the longest running US game show?", "answer": "Price is Right", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febb0f17e83c707845b210a", "question": "What is the technical name for having different-colored eyes?", "answer": "Heterchromia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b63f", "question": "What spice comes from the herb called cilantro?", "answer": "Coriander", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f191ff048f679a45aab2", "question": "Is it the female or the male turkey that gobbles?", "answer": "The male gobbles and the female cackles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0ad", "question": "Which US government branch includes the President and Vice President?", "answer": "Executive", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c79c", "question": "What is the name of Neptune's largest moon?", "answer": "Triton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff511a7ff04d658268c92c8", "question": "Who was Canada's longest-serving prime minister?", "answer": "William Lyon Mackenzie King was Canada's longest serving prime minister at 21 years, 154 days, non-consecutively.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339096", "question": "Who were the siblings of the Greek god Hera?", "answer": "Poseidon, Zeus, Hades, Demeter, Hestia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b862", "question": "What word is both a computer programming language and a nickname for coffee?", "answer": "Java", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cdba7e347d002c297e4df", "question": "What do the letters stand for in poet E.E. Cummings' name?", "answer": "Edward Estlin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eb3", "question": "What slogan is painted on the nose of Robert Duvall's Wagner-blasting helicopter in \"Apocalypse Now\"?", "answer": "Death from above", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133931a", "question": "In the 1967 movie \"Cool Hand Luke\", how many hard-boiled eggs does Lucas eat in one hour?", "answer": "50", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c203877e98cb97778983", "question": "Who named the Pacific Ocean?", "answer": "Ferdinand Magellan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133991a", "question": "What was Billy Joel\u2019s first Top 40 hit?", "answer": "Piano Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cfd", "question": "What was the last name of Dennis the Menace's older neighbor that Dennis would consistently bother?", "answer": "Wilson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ae", "question": "The first spin-off of C.S.I., starting in 2002, was set in what city?", "answer": "Miami", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6cc", "question": "What US city and its surroundings is the basis for a standard US Monopoly board?", "answer": "Atlantic City", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071d2c3745b36be73039d5", "question": "What Soviet operation forced over 2,000 scientists and engineers to relocate from East Germany to Russia to work on missile design and production?", "answer": "Operation Osoaviakhim", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60078a310eee65b76b9f265f", "question": "What country's declaration of war triggered the start of World War I?", "answer": "After Bosnian Serb Gavrilo Princip assassinated Archduke Franz Ferdinand, Austria-Hungary declared war on Serbia in July 1914.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fffa3c773838c5c8a417f21", "question": "In 1612, who became the first person to observe Neptune?", "answer": "Galileo Galilei - However, he thought he was observing a star and not a planet.  Therefore, he did not receive credit for discovering the planet.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390cd", "question": "Which is Shakespeare's shortest play?", "answer": "The Comedy of Errors", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b980", "question": "The Acol system is used in which card game?", "answer": "Bridge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be4a", "question": "Keurig Green Mountain is responsible for inventing what product?", "answer": "K-cup pods", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be13", "question": "What specific animal appeared above the \"Don't Tread on Me\" motto on early American flags?", "answer": "A rattlesnake", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071f333745b36be73039e9", "question": "What is Em Cypress' secret in the comic book series \"Revival\"?", "answer": "She is a reviver", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac17", "question": "Victoria is the capital of which country and archipelago located northeast of Madagascar?", "answer": "Seychelles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac6a", "question": "What name was Haitian dictator Francois Duvalier better known by?", "answer": "Papa Doc", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffb57b35dad637d903c880a", "question": "What material did early Venetians use to construct the foundations of their buildings?", "answer": "Wood (Venice's buildings were built on marshy mud and sand.  The wood petrified due to the lack of oxygen in the marshy soil.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339156", "question": "Who said: \"We are more popular than Jesus\"?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e49", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"The Dirty Dozen\"?", "answer": "Jim Brown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133906f", "question": "What US state are a large portion of Stephen King's novels based in?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb9d", "question": "What national news magazine published its first issue in February 1933, as a competitor of \"Time\"?", "answer": "Newsweek", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b476", "question": "What year saw the founding of the Michelin tire company?", "answer": "1889", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffcfc6b9dc5ec6cd98a831c", "question": "What artist hides his portraits in piles of junk?", "answer": "French artist Bernard Pras is widely known for his unbelievable found-object installations.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb01", "question": "The Nintendo character we know as Mario first appeared in what arcade game?", "answer": "Donkey Kong", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015f0d1fe83fe1f2a824c13", "question": "Which country hosted the first decorated Christmas tree?", "answer": "The first decorated Christmas tree was in Riga, Latvia in 1510.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e0", "question": "Who played Mr. Brown in the movie \"Reservoir Dogs\"?", "answer": "Quentin Tarantino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b088", "question": "What year was the Hubble telescope launched into orbit?", "answer": "1990", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ec", "question": "In The Simpsons, Principal Skinner has a picture of what hanging opposite his desk in his office?", "answer": "Springfield Elementary", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c484", "question": "What is the technical name for the shape the stackable Pringles chips have?", "answer": "Hyperbolic Paraboloid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b22b", "question": "Gandhi's famous march to Dandi in 1930 was an act to protest against Great Britain's tax on what?", "answer": "Salt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e8", "question": "What type of radio had a cat's whisker?", "answer": "Crystal set", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133907a", "question": "Who was the Roman god of agriculture?", "answer": "Saturn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aefe", "question": "What treaty ended the American Revolution?", "answer": "Treaty of Paris", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59523dfa736d4be723796b49", "question": "What does the \"Calgary Stampede\" bills itself as?", "answer": "The Greatest Outdoor Show on Earth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c54f", "question": "What is the name given to the animals that live their lives both in water and on land?", "answer": "Amphibians", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe765e6eec85e375820b279", "question": "What US state's flag has different images on the front and back?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59db788c0ab2c8f322317ff4", "question": "What is the capital of Panama?", "answer": "Panama City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597cdcb9e347d002c297e4ea", "question": "President Richard Nixon called what songstress an \"Ambassador of Love\"?", "answer": "Pearl Baily", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b8cee294b094db915830ab", "question": "Who is credited with creating McDonald\u2019s\u2019 Big Mac?", "answer": "Jim Delligatti", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c78", "question": "What artist was best known for his covers of \"The Saturday Evening Post\"?", "answer": "Norman Rockwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594d05dc1a1c922dd1ac64a5", "question": "What two countries have square flags?", "answer": "Switzerland and Vatican City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b188", "question": "Who succeeded Jimmy Carter as the 40th President of the United States?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393cf", "question": "How old is Sarah in the movie \"Terminator 2\"?", "answer": "29", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f3b", "question": "What two long-running 1980s TV shows featured characters called Uncle Jesse?", "answer": "The Dukes of Hazzard and Full House", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5cb70c36f96e155acab35d2a", "question": "How much did the United States pay Russia per acre for the purchase of Alaska in 1867?", "answer": "About 2 Cents per acre", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d1d", "question": "What German composer was played by Gary Oldman in the film \"Immortal Beloved\"?", "answer": "Beethoven", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4e7c106d333868d34d742", "question": "In what movie theater was Lee Harvey Oswald arrested following the assassination of JFK?", "answer": "The Texas Theater", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd9", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"luau\"?", "answer": "Hawaiian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4dd8306d333868d34d703", "question": "Eric the Red was a Viking from what period of time?", "answer": "900s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef62176ce05a3942286e5b", "question": "What is Tina Turner's real name?", "answer": "Anna Mae Bullock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133966c", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Marge's bowling ball?", "answer": "Homer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bab8", "question": "Which Biblical character wrestled an angel in Genesis 32?", "answer": "Jacob", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1a4", "question": "What were Wilma Flintstone and Betty Rubble's maiden names?", "answer": "Slaghoople and McBricker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133910b", "question": "Viktor Frankl's book \"Man's Search for Meaning\" documents the writers experiences during which war?", "answer": "World War II", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea7aacff048f679a45abed", "question": "The word \"quarantine\" indicates how many days of isolation?", "answer": "40", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7ca04877e98cb97778a00", "question": "What is the capital of the British Virgin Islands?", "answer": "Road Town", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b654", "question": "The hymn for what branch of the US military begins with the line: \"From the halls of Montezuma\"?", "answer": "Marine Corps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133956b", "question": "What was wrong with the Grinch's heart in, How the Grinch Stole Christmas?", "answer": "It was two sizes too small", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffcfea99dc5ec6cd98a832b", "question": "What word did Robert A. Heinlein introduce into the English language in his book \"Stranger in a Strange Land\"?", "answer": "In the 1961 science-fiction novel, Heinlein coined the term Grok, which means \"to understand intuitively or by empathy\".", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5bbd509000d154d7af00b8d7", "question": "Tom DeLonge, Mark Hoppus and Scott Raynor formed which band?", "answer": "Blink-182", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac23", "question": "What countries share land borders with Suriname?", "answer": "French Guiana, Guyana, and Brazil", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef65ff6ce05a3942286e73", "question": "Which famous actress was the first Tool Time Girl on \"Home Improvement\"?", "answer": "Pamela Anderson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b050", "question": "Whose assassination brought Hosni Mubarak to power in Egypt?", "answer": "Anwar Sadat", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beaf", "question": "How many hole cards is each player dealt in Texas Hold 'Em?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338918", "question": "Who became the first person to become a billionaire by writing books?", "answer": "J.K. Rowling", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4a3949076251badbeab1", "question": "In which Texas city will you find the famous Alamo?", "answer": "San Antonio -- The old mission was the site of a doomed battle in Texas\u2019s war for independence from Mexico.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac79", "question": "During which American period did stock car racing gain most of its popularity?", "answer": "The Prohibition", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b91b", "question": "What does the abbreviation \"AT&T\" stand for?", "answer": "American Telephone and Telegraph Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c454", "question": "What is the name for a baby crocodile?", "answer": "Crocklet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c681", "question": "Layers of soil are known as what?", "answer": "Horizons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015f62afe83fe1f2a824c1c", "question": "During which period in Japanese history did \"Seven Samurai\" take place?", "answer": "Sengoku", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fb08298cf631c2414a13b46", "question": "How many soccer players should each team typically hove on the field at the start of each match?", "answer": "11", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c532", "question": "What two dogs are bred to make a puggle?", "answer": "Pug and beagle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398ee", "question": "What movie won the 2012 Best Picture Golden Globe Award for a Drama?", "answer": "The Descendents", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be5d", "question": "What is the only US state to boast a radio station whose call letters are the exact same name of the city?", "answer": "Waco", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c740", "question": "What is the most populous bird in the world?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c68", "question": "What was the name of John Travolta's character in the 1977 movie \"Saturday Night Fever\"?", "answer": "Tony Manero", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c03", "question": "What psychologist's autobiography was titled \"Flashbacks\"?", "answer": "Timothy Leary", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600a274ee958e8c9f3127314", "question": "Who is the city of Regina, Saskatchewan named for?", "answer": "Queen Victoria - Originally a hunters\u2019 camp named Pile O\u2019Bones, the settlement was renamed Regina, Latin for \"queen\".", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c6", "question": "Where is Mount Olympus?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bac2", "question": "What do the letters YMCA stand for?", "answer": "Young Men\u2019s Christian Association", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1db", "question": "Greeks consider Tuesday the unluckiest day of the week because what city fell on a Tuesday in 1453?", "answer": "Constantinople", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339321", "question": "In the movie \"Hangover\", what name did Alan use to refer to his circle of friends?", "answer": "The wolf pack", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c50efbde8045e48466a6", "question": "What is a phanerogam?", "answer": "Plants that produce seeds -- The most advanced plants on the evolutionary scale, they used to go by the name spermatophytes.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ce", "question": "In a P2P network, what does the \"P\" stand for?", "answer": "Peer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395cb", "question": "In The Simpsons, when Homer is trying to think un-sexy thoughts, he imagines who in a bikini?", "answer": "Barney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aff", "question": "What was Radar's real first name on the sitcom \"M*A*S*H\"?", "answer": "Walter", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b372061c3f17ccc40c8e21", "question": "The detective novel \"The Body in the library\" was written by which novelist?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "art"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae62", "question": "The sale of what was prohibited in the US during The Prohibition?", "answer": "Alcohol", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c99afbde8045e48466f0", "question": "How many plates make up the Earth's crust?", "answer": "15 -- The Earth's crust is made up with 7 major and 8 minor plates.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5df", "question": "What color is known as \"vert\" on a coat of arms?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe37af80ada16518afdc05e", "question": "What action did the U.S. take along with Great Britain and Australia after Japan seized Indochina?", "answer": "They formed a trade embargo that cut off 90% of Japan's oil supply", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c8a4a490aac110e416706d", "question": "What are the four primary ingredients in beer?", "answer": "Malt, hops, yeast, water", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5901d8c7709c1c34536e6ea7", "question": "In what country was the first coin operated slot machine invented?", "answer": "US", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b0ea41964118b2bb3809d0", "question": "What year did the \"ILOVEYOU\" virus began infecting computers worldwide?", "answer": "2000", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a186", "question": "In the cartoon \"Wacky Races\", who drove the Crimson Haybaler?", "answer": "The Red Max", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb8d", "question": "What Christian sect observes its Sabbath on Saturday?", "answer": "Seventh-Day Adventists", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1cb", "question": "Which group had a hit with the song \"Back for Good\" in 1995?", "answer": "Take That", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d3852596a59cbdfbd39b", "question": "What message did the original computer virus display?", "answer": "I'm the creeper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60136eff1381754895396372", "question": "In the film \"The Green Mile\", what was the brand of Mr. Jingles cigar box?", "answer": "Marsh Wheeling -- It is the oldest cigar manufacturer in the U.S.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d6e", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"A Tale of the Christ\"?", "answer": "Ben-Hur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b232", "question": "Who, per her dying wish, is buried next to Wild Bill Hickok?", "answer": "Calamity Jane", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a15", "question": "What was the title of the 2003 Russell Crowe movie that was subtitled \"The Far Side of the World\"?", "answer": "Master and Commander", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c39b", "question": "A baby guinea pig is called what?", "answer": "A pup", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60173fb844491cbd7c5a17b5", "question": "What was created by the people who produced the academic journal called the\u00a0\"Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists\" in 1947?", "answer": "The Doomsday Clock -- It was created after humanity entered the Nuclear Age after the dropping of atomic bombs on Japan in 1945.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60121c5c63c99d48cd169b16", "question": "What is the name of Norman Rockwell\u2019s painting depicting a family holiday dinner?", "answer": "\"Freedom from Want\" -- It shows what many people picture to be the ideal Thanksgiving or Christmas dinner.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ccf7965b37b32637bdc44be", "question": "What shape is a wombat\u2019s fecal matter?", "answer": "Cubic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8ff", "question": "What are you doing if you \"yarn over\" or \"pop corn\"?", "answer": "Knitting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c844", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the amygdala?", "answer": "The brain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d10", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"On the Rocks\"?", "answer": "Arthur", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c7b", "question": "Who wrote the 1939 novel \"The Grapes of Wrath\"?", "answer": "John Steinbeck", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ea", "question": "Which 1985 song was co-written by Michael Jackson and Lionel Richie?", "answer": "We Are The World", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6998f20565ad31a57c748", "question": "What were the names of the Doberman Pinschers on \"Magnum P.I.\"?", "answer": "Zeus and Apollo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b19c", "question": "What dog breed was the official 1972 Summer Olympics mascot?", "answer": "Dachshund", "category": "history"}, {"id": "592eadc3f83302ff91e46480", "question": "How is Alistair Leslie Graham better known as on TV?", "answer": "Ali G", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f7167a9e54d890926f6df", "question": "What is the family name of the ruling dynasty of Monaco?", "answer": "Grimaldi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339390", "question": "What is the name of the third Austin Powers movie?", "answer": "Austin Powers in Goldmember", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c70a", "question": "What element's atomic symbol is \"Co\"?", "answer": "Cobalt", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c262", "question": "What is the common word for a metric ton in the US?", "answer": "A tonne", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5d7", "question": "Which quarter of New Orleans is famous for its restaurants and jazz clubs?", "answer": "French Quarter", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015ec11fe83fe1f2a824bfb", "question": "In 2010, how did news organization ProPublica make Pulitzer history?", "answer": "First online-only publisher to win", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcfe", "question": "What did the letter Q originally stand for in NASDAQ?", "answer": "Quotations", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a876", "question": "In what city would you find \"Peachtree Street\"?", "answer": "Atlanta", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b3711b1c3f17ccc40c8e1c", "question": "Considered to be the oldest pub in the US, what year was the White Horse Tavern of Rhode Island opened in?", "answer": "1673", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca78", "question": "\"Fagus\" is the Latin name of what type of tree?", "answer": "Beech", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b43a", "question": "When was Albert Einstein born?", "answer": "1879", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b084", "question": "What object did Ben Franklin attach to the end of a kite string to prove that lightning is electricity?", "answer": "A metal key", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339509", "question": "What is the name of John Carpenter's first feature movie?", "answer": "Dark Star", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e7", "question": "What singer first hit #1 in 1984 with \"Caribbean Queen (No More Love on the Run)\"?", "answer": "Billy Ocean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c788", "question": "Approximately, how far is the Earth's ozone layer from its surface?", "answer": "20 to 30 km", "category": "science"}]